柯克：舰长日志，星历5121.5
KIRK: Captain's log, stardate 5121.5.
绕着米纳里亚星系的第二颗行星运行
Orbiting the second planet in the Minarian star system.
有证据表明这颗恒星进入了新星爆发阶段
This star has given evidence of entering a nova phase
六个月前，建了一个站点来研究
and six months ago, a station was established to make studies of the star
这颗恒星的最后阶段
as its end approaches.
米纳拉正进入临界时期
Minara is now entering a critical period
和企业号被命令来撤离研究站
and the Enterprise has been ordered to evacuate the station.
然而，我们试图联系该站工作人员的尝试并未成功
Yet our attempts to contact the station's personnel have been unsuccessful.
灰尘，显然这些仪器最近没有使用过
Dust. Apparently these instruments have not been recently used.
录音带，也许它会告诉我们一些关于人员的事情[通讯器哔哔声]
Record tape. Maybe it'll tell us something about the personnel that lived here. [Communicator Beeps]
斯科提[通过无线电]：企业号呼叫柯克舰长，请回答
SCOTTY [OVER RADIO]: Enterprise to Captain Kirk. Come in.
我是柯克，怎么了，企业号？
Kirk here. What is it, Enterprise?
我是斯科特，我们的仪器发现了巨大的太阳耀斑
Scott here, sir. Our instruments have picked up a gigantic solar flare
伴随着高强度的宇宙射线
with high levels of cosmic rays accompanying it.
- 有多糟糕？  - 极其巨大
- How bad? - An enormous one.
我们的传感器显示宇宙射线为里特3.51级
Our sensors indicate the cosmic ray measures 3.51 on the Ritter scale.
那对船员和飞船来说都很糟糕
That will play the devil with the crew and ship.
按照这个速度，风暴需要74.1个太阳小时才能过去
At that rate, it will take 74.1 solar hours for the storm to pass.
让船离开这里，保持最小距离
Get the ship out of here. Stay at minimum distance.
- 是的，长官，我们会传送你们上来…  - 不用，我们留在这里，大气层会保护我们
- Aye, aye, sir. We'll beam you up in... - Negative. We're staying here. The atmosphere will protect us.
- 让飞船离开这里  - 那好吧，通话完毕
- Get that ship out of here. - Very well. Scott out.
那盘磁带呢？
What about that tape?
请记住，舰长，我们在此录像带上看到的内容发生在约三个月前
Remember, Captain, what we see on this tape happened three months ago.
我认为我不能在这个被上帝遗忘的地方再坚持一周
I don't think I can stand another week in this godforsaken place.
“地的深处在他手中”
"In His hand are the deep places of the earth."
诗篇第95章，第4段，看起来他在听
Psalm 95, verse 4. Looks like he was listening.
[尖锐的噪音]
[HUMMING]
谁在下面？
Who's down there?
他们发生了什么？
What happened to them?
[尖锐的噪音]
[HUMMING]
那声音是从哪里来的？史波克，你能定位吗？
Where's that sound coming from? Spock, can you pinpoint it?
否定的，舰长，它没有显示
Negative, Captain. It doesn't register.
老骨头
Bones.
史波克！
Spock!
[隆隆声]
[EXPLOSION]
柯克：太空，最后的边界
KIRK: Space, the final frontier.
这些是星舰的航行企业号
These are the voyages of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年使命：探索陌生的新世界
Its five-year mission: To explore strange new worlds,
寻找新生命和新文明
to seek out new life and new civilizations,
勇敢地去以前没有人去过的地方
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
史波克，老骨头
Spock. Bones.
我们在哪？
Where are we?
正好在行星表面以下121.32米，舰长
Exactly 121.32 metres beneath the planet's surface, Captain.
- 我们是怎么到这里来的？  - 被一个物质能量扰频器传送过来的
- How did we get here? - Beamed by a matter-energy scrambler
类似于我们的传送装置
similar to our transporter mechanism.
- 伤口很严重，痛吗？  - 不
- That's a nasty cut. Does it hurt? - No.
测量到一个生命读数，方为42，标记7
Getting a life-form reading, bearing 42, mark 7.
- 失踪的科学家之一？  - 不，类人动物，但绝不是智人
- One of the missing scientists? - No. Humanoid but not homo sapiens.
- 鉴定？  - 不可能
- Identification? - Impossible.
我无法鉴定非类人生物
I can make no identification other than it being humanoid.
让我们来弄明白，相位枪击晕模式
Let's find out. Phasers on stun.
接近生命形式，舰长
Approaching the life-form.
- 它是什么？  - 仍然难以辨别
- What is it? - Still undistinguishable.
- 当心  - 为何，她看起来足够无害
- Be careful. - Why? She seems harmless enough.
马纳克四号的沙蝙蝠似乎是无生命的水晶，医生
The sand bats of Manark IV appear to be inanimate rock crystals, Doctor...
直到他们进攻
until they attack.
我们不会伤害你
We're not gonna hurt you.
这是你的家吗？你住在这里吗？
Is this your home? Do you live here?
怎么样，史波克？分析
What about it? Analysis.
根据我们对这个星球的重力和其他因素的了解
From what we know of the gravity and other factors of this planet,
像她这样的生命体无法在这里进化
life-forms such as hers could not evolve here.
你负责把我们带到这里吗？
Are you responsible for bringing us here?
不要害怕，老骨头，她怎么了？
Don't be afraid. Bones, what's wrong with her?
她是个哑巴，吉姆，没有声带
She's a mute. No vocal chords.
甚至没有退化迹象，而且我不认为这是一种病理状态
Not even vestigials. And I don't think it's a pathological condition.
- 解释  - 她看起来很健康
- Explain. - She appears to be healthy.
换句话说，缺少声带是她这个人种的正常生理结构
Lack of vocal chords could be normal for her species, whatever that is.
一个哑巴种族，类似伽马维迪斯四号上的文明
A race of mutes. Like the civilization on Gamma Vertis IV.
这就是我的观察，不管对不对
That's my observation, for what it's worth.
没有语言，她怎么能理解我们的意思呢？
Without speech, how's she going to be able to understand us?
- 除非她是心灵感应者  - 一种不太可能的可能性，舰长
- Unless she's a telepath. - An unlikely possibility.
因为98%的心灵感应物种发送思想并且接收思想
Since 98% of the telepathic species send thoughts as well as receive them.
她没有试图接触我们的思想
She's made no attempt to contact our minds.
我们不能一直称她为“她”，就好像她不在这里一样
We can't keep referring to her as "she" as if she weren't here.
你有何高见？
Do you have any idea?
我不知道你们，但我要叫她宝石
I don't know about you but I'm gonna call her Gem.
- 宝石，医生？  - 嗯，总比“嘿，你”要好
- Gem, Doctor? - That's better than "Hey, you".
我想知道我们为什么在这里
I want to know why we're here.
我想知道这是怎么回事
I want to know what's going on.
而她知道
And she knows.
- 我是舰长  - 我们知道你的身份，舰长
- I'm Captain... - We are aware of your identity.
你们是谁？你们为什么带我们来这里？
Who are you? Why did you bring us here?
我们是维恩人，不要插手
We are Vians. Do not interfere.
- 你打算对我们做什么？  - 不要再耽误我们了
- What do you intend to do with us? - Delay us no longer.
我们来…
We come...
既然你已经知道我们是谁，你也一定知道我们是和平而来的
Since you already know who we are, you must also know we come in peace.
我们的首要指令明确禁止我们干涉…
Our Prime Directive specifically prohibits us from interference...
我好像站不起来了
I can't seem to stand up.
不要对抗力场
Don't fight the force field.
有一些东西会扰乱身体的新陈代谢
There's something about it that upsets the body metabolism.
不完全是，医生，场从你的身体中汲取能量
Not quite, Doctor. The field draws its energy from your bodies.
你越抵抗，力场就越强
The more you resist, the stronger the force field becomes.
哈，足够了
Sufficient.
史波克
Spock.
除了我们刚才看到的那个出口之外，肯定还有一个出口
There must be an exit other than the one we just saw.
正确，舰长
Correct, Captain.
- 你感觉还好吗？  - 别担心我
- Do you feel all right? - Don't worry about me.
他们可能伤害了她
They may have hurt her.
他们伤害了你吗？
Did they hurt you?
疼痛消失了
The pain is gone.
她摸了摸我的头，疼痛消失了
She touched my head and the pain is gone.
伤口已经完全愈合
The wound is completely healed.
痊愈了，吉姆，她一定是个同理心
It fits, Jim. She must be an empath.
她的神经系统非常敏感，她能感觉到我们的情绪和生理反应
Her nervous system is so sensitive she can feel our emotional reactions.
- 它们成为她的一部分  - 谢谢
- They become part of her. - Thank you.
舰长，在那个方向上，我的三录仪读取到大量的物体
Captain, in that direction, my tricorder is picking up a substantial collection of objects.
- 详细说？  - 电子设备
- Details? - Electronic devices.
我不明白为什么我的三录仪之前没有给出任何指示
I fail to understand why my tricorder previously gave no indication of them.
他们在那里，让我们检查一下
They're there now. Let's check them out.
一个人呆在这里可能很危险，跟我们来
Staying here alone could be dangerous. Come with us.
真有趣
Fascinating.
看看这东西
Look at this stuff.
老骨头，史波克，过来
Bones, Spock, come here.
吉姆，史波克
Jim, Spock.
你们按时到了，一些进一步的简单测试是必要的
We are on schedule. Some further simple tests are necessary.
- 我们已经看到了你们的一些测试结果  - 我找到了我们失踪的人，死了
- We've seen the results of your tests. - I found our missing men. Dead.
- 你的另一个实验？  - 你错了，他们自己的不完美杀死了他们
- Another one of your experiments? - You're wrong. Their own imperfections killed them.
他们不是合适的主题，来
They were not fit subjects. Come.
- 时间不多了  - 是的，你的时间不多了
- Time is short. - Yes. Your time is running out.
太阳即将新星爆发，当它发生时，它会摧毁你们，这个星球和这个疯狂的刑讯室
The sun is about to nova. When it does, it'll destroy you, this planet,  it will destroy this torture chamber.
我们离开这里吧
Let's get out of here.
读数表明通向地表的通道位于这个方向
Readings indicate the passage to the surface lies in this direction.
[风啸]
[WIND HOWLS]
柯克呼叫企业号，柯克呼叫企业号，请回答
Kirk to Enterprise. Kirk to Enterprise. Come in.
超出范围，史波克先生，读数？
Out of range. Readings, Mr. Spock?
研究站在那个方向6公里
Research station 6km in that direction.
我们快过去，如果企业号派了搜查队，一定在那里
Let's get there. If there's a search party, it'll be there.
史波克？
Spock?
还有多远？
Much further?
就在前面
Just ahead.
嘿，吉姆，看，斯科提和搜查队
Hey, Jim, look. Scotty and the search party.
斯科提！斯科提！
Scotty!
呆着那儿！
Stay there!
- 快来  - 我们来了！
- Come on. - We're coming!
继续前进
Keep going.
他们的生存意志是伟大的
Their will to survive is great.
- 他们非常热爱生活，因此而奋斗  - 首要因素
- They love life greatly to struggle so. - The prime ingredient.
他们去哪儿了？
Where did they go?
我想他们从来没有真正出现过，那是海市蜃楼
I believe they were never actually present. It was a mirage.
柯克在哪里？
Where's Kirk?
吉姆
Jim.
你在这里做什么？斯科提在哪里？
What are you doing here? Where's Scotty?
- 舰长，那是海市蜃楼  - 柯克舰长？
- It was a mirage. - Captain Kirk?
我们已经决定一个样本就足够了
We have decided that one specimen will be sufficient.
- 你和我们一起来  - 其他人呢？
- You will come with us. - What about the others?
我们对他们没有兴趣，他们可以走了
We have no interest in them. They may go.
- 很好  - 你不能回去，你会像那两个人一样
- Very well. - You can't go back. You'll end up like the other two.
- 舰长，我请求许可…  - 拒绝
- Captain, I request permission... - Denied.
但是，舰长…
But, Captain...
你接到命令了
You have your orders.
- 我的人怎么了？  - 他们很安全
- What happened to my men? - They are safe.
你说的一个标本，我的人怎么了？
One specimen, you said. What happened to my men?
- 的确，首要因素  - 他们在哪？告诉我！
- Indeed. Prime ingredient. - Where are they? Tell me!
你说你会让他们走
You said you'd let them go.
苏鲁先生
Mr. Sulu.
你能估计一下太阳耀斑还要多久才减弱吗？
Estimate how much longer we'll have until the solar flares subside.
好的，长官
Aye, sir.
读数现在显示里特2.721级
Readings now indicate 2.721 on the Ritter scale.
按照目前的消减速度
At the present rate of decrease,
我们必须等待17个小时才能尝试进入轨道
we'll have to wait 17 hours before we even attempt to enter orbit.
是的
Aye.
好吧，既然我们被困在这里
Well, as long as we're stuck out here,
我们不妨放松一下，直到暴风雨过去
we might as well relax until the storm passes.
风暴持续的时间比我们预期的要长四个小时
Storm's already lasted four hours longer than we'd anticipated.
- 我们的登陆小队会不会有危险？  - 那不太可能
- Could our landing party be in danger? - That's not likely.
这颗行星的大气层将提供保护
The planet's atmosphere will give protection.
如果我了解柯克舰长，他担心我们更甚于我们担心他，哈
If I know Captain Kirk, he'll be more worried about us than we are about him.
- 你想知道什么？  - 我们不寻求你所说的信息
- What is it you want to know? - We seek no information as you mean.
你们的文明太不成熟，对我们来说没有有价值的知识
Your civilization is too immature to have knowledge of value to us.
你不需要我们提供任何知识，但你愿意为此进行杀戮
You don't need any knowledge from us yet you're willing to kill for it.
那就是林克和小坂的遭遇吗？
Is that what happened to Linke and Ozaba?
我们没有杀死他们，他们自己的恐惧杀死了他们
We did not kill them. Their own fears killed them.
那么，你对他们有什么期望？你想从我这里得到什么？
What did you expect from them? And what do you want from me?
我们观察了你激情的强度
We've observed the intensity of your passions,
并衡量了你爱他人的能力
and gauged your capacity to love others.
现在我们希望你向我们展示你的勇气和意志的力量
Now we want you to reveal to us your courage and strength of will.
为什么？
Why?
你希望证明什么？
What is it you hope to prove?
如果我的死有任何意义
If my death is to have any meaning,
至少告诉我我为什么而死
at least tell me what I'm dying for.
如果你活着，你会得到答案的
If you live, you will have your answer.
[呐喊]
[SHOUTS]
过来，史波克，这条通道之前在那里，它一定在那里
Come on. Spock, The passageway was there before. It's gotta be there.
我无法锁定以前的读数，我找不到离开这里的出口
I'm unable to lock in on the previous readings. I can find no exit out of here.
舰长！
Captain!
吉姆，怎么了？他们对你做了什么？
Jim, what is it? What have they done to you?
帮助他，不要害怕帮助他
Help him. Don't be afraid to help him.
吉姆…
Jim...
你躺着别动，我马上去检查她
You lie still. I'll check her out right away.
- 她会活下来吗？  - 她现在看起来很好
- Will she live? - She seems fine now.
你能解释一下发生了什么吗？
Can you explain what happened?
完全的移情作用，她一定是个完全功能性移情者
Complete empathy. She must be a totally functional empath.
她的神经系统与你的神经系统相连，以抵消你最坏的症状
Her nervous system connected to yours to counteract the worst of your symptoms.
她实际上用她的力维持着你身体的生理反应
With her strength, she sustained your body's physiological reactions.
她变虚弱了，我能感觉到，她有生命危险吗？
She weakened. I could feel it. Is her life in danger?
还很难说，但为你的身体提供生命支持确实耗尽了她
It's hard to say yet, but supplying your body with life did drain her.
她退缩似乎暗示了对死亡的恐惧，医生
Her withdrawal suggested the fear of death, Doctor.
只是你催促了，她才继续
Only your urging caused her to continue.
的确，恐惧自然是她的第一反应
That's true. Fear would be a first reaction.
也许她对我们的舰长不够了解，无法为他献出生命
Perhaps she doesn't know our captain well enough to offer her life for him.
这样的损耗会杀死她吗？
Could the strain have killed her?
是的，但我认为她的自我保护本能会插手阻止
I would assume that her instinct for self-preservation would take over to prevent it.
你感觉怎么样？
How do you feel?
我累了
I'm... tired.
你能回忆起发生了什么吗，舰长？
Can you recall what happened, Captain?
我记得实验室，而且…他们想知道一些事情
I remember the laboratory and... they wanted to know something.
- 我不记得了  - 放松
- I can't remember. - Take it easy.
- 我怎么了？  - 你有减压病的症状
- What's the matter with me? - You have symptoms of the bends.
血液中的氮气气泡会导致疼痛
Nitrogen bubbles in your blood cause the pain.
- 但是你怎么会在这儿得减压病？  - 你得去问维恩人
- How do you get the bends down here? - You'll have to ask the Vians.
- 我会活下来吗？  - 你需要在减压室里呆一会儿
- Will I live? - Well, you could use some time in a decompression chamber.
否则，我会说你的康复是奇迹
Otherwise I'd say your recovery is miraculous.
我希望是我的功劳，可惜是她干的
I wish I could take the credit but she did the work.
舰长，我注意到当你从维恩人的实验室回来时，有一束光在你前面
Captain, I noted that a light preceded you when you returned from the Vians' laboratory.
- 为什么你这么喜欢分析？  - 他是对的，继续
- Why are you getting analytical? - He's right. Continue.
我推断这种光是将设备连接到能源的能量传输点
Such a light is an energy transfer point linking this device to the power source.
你能利用它吗？
Can you tap into it?
如果我确定它使用的频率，我也许能让它为我们工作
If I determine the frequency it uses, I can cause it to function for us.
并按照他们带我们进来的方式带我们出去
And get us out the way they brought us in.
- 我也这样认为  - 继续研究
- I would say so. - I would say proceed.
你被称为舰长
You are called Captain.
你对你的船员负责，对吗？
You are responsible for your crew. Is this correct?
- 是的  - 我们的工作需要你的一个手下的合作
- It is. - We find it necessary to have the cooperation of one of your men in our efforts.
- 我们不会合作  - 当我们继续我们的审讯时
- We will not cooperate. - When we resume our interrogations,
你会决堤个我们将用你的哪个手下
you will decide which of your men we shall use.
重要的是，医生有87%的死亡几率
It is essential. There is an 87% chance that the doctor will die.
虽然史波克的生命没有危险，但有93%的几率
And while Spock's life is not in danger, the possibility is 93%
遭受脑损伤，导致永久性精神失常
that he will suffer brain damage resulting in permanent insanity.
- 怎么样了，史波克？  - 我不知道，舰长
- How's it going? - I do not know.
我了解它的运行原理，但仅此而已
I understand its operating principles but that is all.
用不了多久，维恩人就会回来，尽快了解它是如何工作的
It won't be long before the Vians come back. Find out how it works. Soon.
别紧张
Take it easy.
人并不打算生活在这么深的地下，不自然
Men can't live underground. It's not natural.
太空旅行自然吗？
And space travel is?
有些人在地面以下的矿井中度过一生
Some men spend their lives in mines beneath the surface.
我是医生，不是煤矿工人
I'm a doctor, not a coal miner.
医生，我已经在三录仪上记录了我的原理和理论
I've recorded my principles and theories.
如果维恩人回来，有足够的数据供你何舰长完成调整
Should the Vians return, there's sufficient data for you and the captain to complete the adjustments.
我不是机械师，不管你留下了多少笔记，我都没法让它工作
I'm not a mechanic. I couldn't get that to work however many notes you left.
可能不是，但是你和舰长一起就能做到
Possibly not. But you and the captain together will be able to do so.
无论如何，你是合乎逻辑的与舰长一起离开的人
In any case, you are the logical one to leave with the captain.
决定权在我
The decision is mine.
如果要做任何决定，我来做…
If there are any decisions to be made, I'll make them...
如果有必要
if and when it becomes necessary.
- 我不需要任何…  - 我仍然是首席医疗官
- I don't need any... - I'm still chief medical officer.
我会告诉你你需要什么，什么时候，你宁愿得减压病吗？
I'll tell you what you need and when. Would you rather have the bends?
就这样，只是躺下来放松一下
That's it. Just lie down and relax.
他要睡多久，医生？
How long will he be asleep, Doctor?
在情绪紧张和减压病发作之间，他的状态很糟糕
Between the emotional strain and that attack of bends, he's in bad shape.
我不是在批评你的行为，相反
I'm not criticising your action. On the contrary.
我很感激它，他将免于做出如此艰难的决定所带来的压力
I'm grateful for it. He will be spared the strain of making so difficult a decision.
- 你大大简化了情况  - 如何？
- You simplify the situation considerably. - How?
当舰长睡着后，我负责指挥
While the captain is asleep, I am in command.
当维恩人回来时，我就跟他们一起去
When the Vians return, I shall go with them.
- 如果我没有给他那一针…  - 选择权会是他的
- If I hadn't given him that shot... - The choice would have been his.
现在它是我的了
Now it is mine.
你的行为是非常不道德的
Your action is highly unethical.
我的决定…成立
My decision... stands.
嗯…嗯…
Um... Um...
不是这次，史波克
Not this time, Spock.
选择已经做好了
The choice has been made.
和我的朋友一起呆在这里，他们会照顾你的
Stay here with my friends. They'll take care of you.
你明白吗？
Do you understand?
那就来吧
Come, then.
医生
Doctor.
如果有任何其他方法可以实现我们的目的…
If there was any other way to accomplish our purpose...
那就做吧
Get on with it.
- 你为什么让他这么做？  - 我和你一样被说服了
- Why did you let him do it? - I was convinced just like you were.
- 被我们的好医生用针  - 有进展吗？
- By the good doctor's hypo. - Anything?
唔…
Hmm...
很少见的设备，是一个控制单元，但不是一个控制装置
A most unusual device. A control unit, but not a control mechanism.
- 它不是机械装置  - 它究竟是什么？
- It is not a mechanical device. - What is it?
这个装置与一种电能量模式相协调
It's attuned to only one electrical pattern of energy,
这种模式是由拥有它的人的精神冲动产生的
the pattern produced by the mental impulses of the person who possesses it.
它仅由精神命令激活
It is activated solely by mental commands.
你能重新调整它，以适应我们的大脑模式吗？
Can you adapt it, re-attune it, to fit our brain patterns?
我会尝试的，但是一次不能适应多个模式
I shall attempt it. But it is not possible to fit more than one pattern at a time.
我熟悉我自己的模式，有了你的许可…
I am familiar with my own pattern. With your permission...
随你做什么只要让它工作
Do what you have to do to make it work.
令我不安的是为什么维恩人让我们保留它
What disturbs me is why the Vians let us keep it.
真有趣，他们一定知道我们有能力理解和使用这个装置
They must know we are capable of comprehending and using this control.
- 我们会用它来逃脱  - 合逻辑假设是
- And that we would use it to escape. - The logical assumption
他们想让我们走
is that they wish to let us go.
- 他们留下了麦考伊  - 那显然是他们的意图
- And they keep McCoy. - That is evidently their intention.
不知何故，你是这一切的症结和焦点
Somehow, you're the crux, the focal point of all this.
在我们到达这里之前，她是一名囚犯，他们没有伤害或威胁她
Before we got here, she was a prisoner. They didn't hurt or threaten her.
事实表明她对他们的目的至关重要
The facts would indicate she is essential to their purpose.
是的，有目的，但目的是什么？
Yes, there is a purpose, but what is it?
对你来说，所有的痛苦和恐惧是自己发生的，还是故意为之？
Has all the pain and terror happened, or been made to happen, for you?
好了，舰长，调整很脆弱，可能无法使用一次以上
Completed. Adjustments are delicate and may not survive more than one use.
但是，应该有足够的能量将我们传送到企业号上
However, there should be sufficient energy to transfer us to the Enterprise.
- 能带我们去找麦考伊吗？  - 如果你想的话
- Will it take us to McCoy? - If you so desire.
最好的防守是强大的进攻，我打算现在就开始进攻
The best defense is a strong offense. I intend to start offending right now.
以实验室为目标
Aim for the lab.
老骨头…
Bones...
史波克
Spock.
把他弄下来
Get him down.
他的手腕
His wrists.
他的脉搏几乎没有了
His pulse is almost gone.
- 他怎么样？  - 严重的心脏损伤
- How is he? - Severe heart damage.
双肺充血的迹象，循环衰竭的症状
Signs of congestion in both lungs. Evidence of circulatory collapse.
[喘气]
[GASPS]
别说话
Don't talk.
别说话，放轻松，直到我们把你送回船上
Don't speak. Take it easy until we get you back to the ship.
怎么了？有什么麻烦？  - 他快死了，吉姆
- What is it? What's the matter? - He's dying, Jim.
- 我们能让他舒服一些，但仅此而已  - 你不知道，你不是医生
- We can only make him comfortable. - You don't know. You're not a doctor.
[麦考伊耳语]
[MCCOY WHISPERS]
内伤，胸部和腹部出血
Internal injuries. Bleeding in chest and abdomen.
脾脏和肝脏大出血
Haemorrhage of the spleen and liver.
70%肾衰竭
70% kidney failure.
他是对的，做医生有它的缺点
He's right. Being a doctor has its drawbacks.
我一直想知道为什么我…[咳嗽]
I always wondered why I... [COUGHS]
麦考伊：谢谢
McCOY: Thanks.
还能活多久？
How long?
随时可能死亡
It could happen any time.
正确的医学用语，嗯，史波克？
The correct medical phrase, eh, Spock?
你对病人的态度很好，史波克
You've got a good bedside manner, Spock.
我们不能做点什么吗？
Can't we do something?
恐怕不能
I'm afraid not.
宝石或许能帮助他，像她帮助我一样
Gem might be able to help him the way she helped me.
但他的濒临死亡会杀死她吗？
But could his nearness to death also kill her?
不确定，麦考伊对她反应的分析
Uncertain. McCoy's analysis of her reaction
假设自我保护本能会阻止它
assumes that her instinct for self-preservation would prevent it.
- 但我们不能确定  - 如果她能让他变得强壮
- But we cannot be positive. - If she could just strengthen him
不让他陷入死亡，我们说不定还能救他
and keep him from sinking into death, we might be able to save him.
不允许干扰
No interference will be permitted.
她可以救他一命，让我们帮她去找他
She can save his life. Let us help her to go to him.
不应敦促她采取行动
She must not be urged to take action.
一切都必须在不受干扰的情况下进行  - 把我们带到一起的目的…
- All must proceed without interference. - The purpose that brought us...
除了满足你们的需要之外，这一切还有什么目的？
What purpose can all this serve except to fulfil a need of yours?
我们的一生只剩下一种需要，看看我们测试的完成情况
We have but one need left in life. To see the completion of our test.
- 要有耐心  - 耐心？我们的朋友快死了
- Be patient. - Patient? Our friend is dying.
也许
Perhaps.
除了带给你愉悦之外，还有什么目的？
What purpose can be served except to bring you pleasure?
当然你知道你们的星系很快就会灭绝
Surely you know that your star system will soon be extinct.
- 你们的太阳会新星爆发  - 我们知道
- Your sun will nova. - We know.
它行星上的数百万居民注定要灭亡
The millions of inhabitants on its planets are doomed.
这就是为什么我们在此
That is why we are here.
你为了取悦自己而设计的这个死亡竞技场
This arena of death that you've devised for your pleasure.
- 能阻止这场灾难吗？  - 不，不会
- Will it prevent this catastrophe? - No, it will not.
但也许能拯救宝石的星球
But it may save Gem's planet.
在米纳拉的所有行星中，我们只能将其中一个行星的居民运送到安全的地方
Of all the planets of Minara, we can only transport inhabitants of one to safety.
如果宝石的星球是将被拯救的星球
If Gem's planet is the one that will be saved,
我们必须毫无疑问地确定他们值得幸存
we must make certain beyond any doubt they are worthy of survival.
我们朋友的死对这个目的有什么用？
How will the death of our friend serve this purpose?
他的死没有帮助
His death will not serve it.
但她为他付出生命的意愿有
But her willingness to give her life for him will.
- 你们是她的老师  - 我们是？
- You were her teachers. - We were?
- 她能从我们身上学到什么？  - 你的生存意志
- What could she learn from us? - Your will to survive.
你对生活的热爱，你们求知的激情
Your love of life. Your passion to know.
她的种族会记住这些
They're recorded in her being.
她的星球将是幸运的
Her planet will be fortunate.
你们每个人都愿意为他人献出自己的生命
Each of you would give his life for the others.
我们必须查明这种本能是否已经传递给了宝石
We must find out whether that instinct has been transmitted to Gem.
[隆隆声]
[RUMBLING]
- 时间越来越短  - 你是对的，舰长
- Time grows short. - You were correct, Captain.
这里发生的一切都是他们造成的
Everything that has occurred here has been caused by them.
这是一个很棒的实验室，我们一直是研究对象
This has been a great laboratory and we have been the subjects.
不，我们只创造了环境，那是必要的
No. We only created the circumstances. That was necessary.
你的行为是自发的
Your actions were spontaneous.
你已经揭示了所有物种中最真实和最好的一切
Everything truest and best in all species of beings has been revealed by you.
那些是使文明值得生存的品质
Those are the qualities that make a civilization worthy to survive.
看吧
Behold.
那是最重要的
That is most significant.
她的种族正在产生一种新的本能
An instinct new to the essence of her being is generating.
同情他人
Compassion for another
正在成为她生命的一部分
is becoming part of her functioning life system.
她害怕
She's afraid.
她在自救
She's saving herself.
她还没有拯救她的人民的本能
She does not yet have the instinct to save her people.
- 我们失败了？  - 不
- We have failed? - No.
还没有
No, not yet.
舰长，麦考伊医生的生活不仅仅依赖于宝石
Captain. Dr. McCoy's life is not solely dependant on Gem.
维恩人也一定能挽救他的生命
The Vians too must be capable of saving his life.
- 是的  - 你不能让他死
- True. - You cannot let him die.
他的死并不重要
His death is not important.
我们必须看看她的自我牺牲的本能
We must see whether her instinct for self-sacrifice
是否已经超过了她的自我保护本能
has become stronger than her instinct for self-preservation.
[咳嗽]
[COUGHS]
别碰我，离我远点
Don't touch me. Stay away.
- 吉姆，史波克，你在这里？  - 是的，老骨头
- Jim. Spock. Are you here? - Yes, Bones.
不要让她碰我，她会死的
Don't let her touch me. She'll die.
吉姆…
Jim...
就算是为了救我自己，我也不能毁灭生命
I can't destroy life even if it's to save my own.
我不能，你知道的，我不能让你这样做
I can't. You know that. I can't let you do it.
舰长？
Captain?
- 怎么了？  - 强烈的情绪正耗尽我们
- What is it? - The intensity of emotion is draining us
并增强力场
and building up the force field.
- 我知道  - 它从我们身上汲取能量，舰长
- I know. - It draws its energy from us, Captain.
不管我们看到什么，所有的情绪都必须被压制
In spite of what we see, all emotion must be suppressed.
它可能会削弱力场
It might weaken the field.
我会尽力
I'll try.
是的
Yes.
史波克
Spock.
我们不能利用我们的力量来改变正在发生的事情
We cannot use our powers to change what is happening.
- 你必须拯救我们朋友的生命  - 不，我们不会
- You must save the life of our friend. - No. We will not.
必须充分发挥她的本能，测试必须完成
Her instinct must be developed to the fullest. The test must be complete.
成功了，宝石为她的星球赢得了生存权，她献出了自己的生命
It is. Gem earned the right of survival for her planet. She offered her life.
- 只是献出生命还不够充分  - 如果死亡就是你想要的
- To offer is not proof enough. - If death is all you understand,
这里有四条生命给你
here are four lives for you.
我们不会离开我们的朋友
We will not leave our friend.
你已经失去了感受情感的能力，你让宝石体验的情感
You can't feel the emotions you brought Gem here to experience.
你不明白活着是什么意思
You don't understand what it is to live.
爱和同情在你心里已经死了，你你们除了智力什么都没有
Love and compassion are dead in you. You're nothing but intellect.
永别了
Farewell.
- 奇怪的  - 什么让你困惑，舰长？
- Strange. - What is puzzling you?
我并不困惑，我…敬畏
I'm not puzzled. I am... awed.
我同意你，她让我敬畏
I'm with you. She awed me.
不，不，我不是说宝石
I wasn't thinking of Gem.
我在想这是多么难以置信的几率
I was thinking of that element of chance
在无限的空间里，我们遇见宝石
that out in limitless space we should come together with Gem.
舰长，像维恩这样的文明可以消除偶然因素
Captain, the element of chance can be eliminated by a civilization like the Vians.
不是质疑你的计算
Not to dispute your computer,
但从你告诉我的来看，我会说她是一颗价值不菲的珍珠
but from what little you've told me, I'd say she was a pearl of great price.
什么，斯科特？
What, Scott?
你不知道商人的故事吗？
You don't know the story of the merchant?
当商人发现了一颗价值不菲的珍珠时
The merchant, who when he found one pearl of great price,
就去变卖他所有的东西，买了它
went and sold all that he had and bought it.
是的，她就是珍宝，维恩人是买到她还是找到了她
Yes, she was all that. But whether the Vians bought or found her,
都无关紧要，她非常珍贵
makes little difference, she was of great value.
就个人而言，我觉得令人着迷的是，凭借他们所有的科学知识
Personally, I find it fascinating that with all their scientific knowledge,
他们最看重的是善良传统的人类情感
it was good old-fashioned human emotion that they valued the most.
也许瓦肯人应该听听这个
Perhaps the Vulcans should hear about this.
史波克先生，你能给他们讲讲这个新闻吗？
Mr. Spock, can you be prevailed upon to bring them the news?
可能，舰长，我当然会考虑这个想法
Possibly. I shall certainly give the thought all the consideration it is due.
- 苏鲁先生，以曲速2前进，- 是的，长官，曲速2
- Mr. Sulu. Ahead warp factor 2. - Aye, sir. Warp factor 2.